MANOJ REDDY AMIREDDY

A Boston, MA 3 617-435-1707 amireddy.m@northeastern.edu manojreddyamireddy amireddym

SUMMARY (LOOKING FOR SUMMER 2022 INTERNSHIP)

Skilled developer and team member with diverse experience utilizing Java tools for all development environments. Over 4+ years of experience as a Software Developer and worked with a large team of Java developers to maintain and improve company projects. Worked as a Software Development Engineer II and researched on new open source projects and cutting edge technologies that are being used by industries. Also worked on development of Microservices using Java and Spring Boot. Has a lot of efficiency in using cloud services like AWS.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

Fall 2021 - Spring 2023

Master of Science in Information Systems

Boston, MA

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Guwahati

Aug 2013 - May 2017

Bachelors in Electronics and Electrical Engineering

Guwahati, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, SQL, C++, C, JavaScript, Bash, R, HQL, Matlab

Tools: Spring Boot, Spring, Django, Flask, Apache Kafka, Maxwell, Apache Storm, Git, Svn, Ansible, Kubernetes, Terraform,

Nginx, Quartz, Maven, Gradle, Logback, Log4J, Swagger, GraphQl, JFrog

Technologies: AWS, Google BigQuery, Mysql, MongoDb, CouchDb, Redis, Jenkins, Docker, Zookeeper, Prometheus, Grafana

Operating Systems: Linux, Mac OS, Windows

EXPERIENCE

Kaleidofin India Private Ltd (FinTech)

Sep 2019 - Aug 2021

Software Development Engineer-II

Chennai, India

- Migrated all monolithic applications into a microservices using the best application design patterns from Spring Framework ecosystem.
- Implemented the best in class technology to monitor and alert the developers in case of any failure or scaling issues in the Production Infrastructure 24/7.
- Played a crucial part in Migrating the whole microservies to a high scalable and availability (99.99%) platform with Kubernetes and Docker containers.
- Worked on revamping the Android app codebase to meet the new Android **10** and **11** version updates and also added UI changes in the Application.

Next Education India Pvt Ltd (EduTech)

June 2017 - July 2019

Research and Development Engineer (Core-Infra)

Hyderabad, India

- Designed a mechanism to scale the applications smoothly and cost effectively (upto **35**%) and also to meet the growing requests per minute by our **12M** customers.
- Worked on implementing the rate limiting setup and firewall protection for all the applications in the Infrastructure to prevent from DDOS attacks.
- Designed and developed the pipelines for sending bulk mobile messages and Emails to the teachers, students and parents by using the asynchronous message queues.
- Developed backend apis in a microservice for Subscription based video delivery platform.
- Worked with DevOps teams to secure the AWS Access keys for mitigating potential security threats.
- Worked on the Nightly Shutdown of the Dev, QA, Pre-Prod Environments for Cost Optimizations.

Anblicks (Cappius Technologies Inc)

May 2016 - July 2016

Intern

Hyderabad, India

• Developed a Computational model for Customer churn analysis and Insurance claim prediction by using the data and Machine learning techniques with an accuracy of **93.4**% and **90.7**% respectively.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Text Generation using Recurrent Neural Network | *Python, RNN, LSTM, flask*

July 2016

- Designed and modeled a text generation model using LSTM and RNN based Neural Networks.
- Developed a Django based web application to generate the text from the user inputs and then compared the models results against the accuracy of prediction and plotted the comparison charts.

Face and Alphabet Recognition | *Python, TensorFlow, Keras*

Feb 2016

• Designed and modeled a Convolutional Neural Network model to train and test the Face and Alphabet recognition on the Image set. Obtained an accuracy of **91.5**% on the face and **99.3**% on alphabet recognition respectively.